

Shenin Francies

Data Science | Medical Engineer

Detail-oriented Data Scientist, with strong analytical and technical skills, guided by the passion to work towards a unified cause. Recent graduate of Medical Engineering who conducts independent researches. Conversant in culture diversity due to exposure to international relations based off of studying and living in India, Kuwait, United Arab Emirates and Germany.

sheninfrancis23@gmail.com

Parananthapuram, Kerala, India

S sheninfrancis23

+91 88 48 44 35 14

in linkedin.com/in/shenin-francies

github.com/SheninFrancies

EDUCATION

Biomedical Engineering, MSc Hochschule Furtwangen University

09/2019 - 02/2022 Baden-Württemberg, Germany

Courses

Physiological Modelling
 Artificial Intelligence

EU Regulatory Affairs
 Artificial Organs

Electrical and Electronics Engineering, BEng. Heriot-Watt University

09/2016 - 11/2019 Dubai, United Arab Emirates

Courses

Control Systems and
 MATLAB and Simulink
 System Theory

C and C++ Programming
 Mechanical Design

WORK EXPERIENCE

Intern - Data Science and Machine Learning Luminar Technolab

07/2022 - Present Kerala, India

Tasks

- Preprocessing of Datasets using Python libraries such as NumPy and Pandas.
- Applied Supervised and Unsupervised Machine Learning techniques on datasets to derive meaningful insights from the model.
- Familiarized with Deep Learning frameworks such as TensorFlow and Keras.
- Skilled in employing Data visualization tools such as Tableau and PowerBI.

Research Assistant

Hochschule Furtwangen University

08/2021 - 09/2021 Baden-Württemberg, Germany

Tasks

- Researched the Two- and Four-Electrode methods in Electrical Impedance Tomography.
- Built circuits and assessed the signal strength.
- Improved the circuit for optimal performance.

Contact: Dr. Alberto Battistel - baa@hs-furtwangen.de

SKILLS

TensorFlow Keras Scikit-learn & SciPy

Apache Spark Pandas & NumPy MATLAB

Amazon Web Services Medical Device Calibration

Tableau PowerBI NLP Microsoft Office

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Application of Deep Learning and Machine Learning (12/2022 - Present)

- .Scavenging data from the internet and employing ML/DL Techniques.

Applications of Machine Learning in Healthcare (11/2022 - 12/2022)

- Implemented Machine Learning algorithms to make predictions on various healthcare datasets.

CERTIFICATES

Applied Data Science with Python - Level 2 (11/2022 - 12/2022)

Big Data Foundations - Level 2 (11/2022 - 12/2022)

Calibration and Testing of Medical Devices (09/2022 - 10/2022)

Cyrix Healthcare Pvt. Ltd.

LANGUAGES

Malayalam English

Native or Bilingual Proficiency Native or Bilingual Proficiency

Full Professional Proficiency

Elementary Proficiency

INTERESTS

AI in Healthcare | Medical Technology

Literature